Mr. Sweezy is a public sector technology industry leader, having served as the CIO of a Federal government agency and at Salesforce as an industry expert in CRM digital strategy for government. As a government technology policy expert, he earned <u>praise from U.S. Congress</u> and recognition by industry leaders as <u>one of the Federal 100</u> most influential voices in the government technology management community. He continued that tradition as a leading industry voice at Salesforce, representing the Fortune 500 company at multiple government technology events and in publications, as well as internal digital strategy for Federal civilian customers. His customer-level support directly influenced over \$4m per year in closed deals' additional contract value.

As the Chief Information Officer for a Federal agency, he led the establishment of a new IT management team, migration to Microsoft Azure and Office 365, and a unified digital services office--while operating at a 62% IT budget cut. Following his review of the IT management functions at the agency, the agency adopted a project-based budget for the first time ever, to implement the 90 reform projects developed to mitigate risks identified through the OCIO review. As a result, the agency migrated to a cloud-based infrastructure, reduced IT issues by 55%, and reduced annual cybersecurity assessment costs by 65%.

At the White House Office of Management and Budget (OMB), Mr. Sweezy developed policy, budget review, and performance management tools to direct the Federal government's over \$80 billion spending in annual technology projects, including as the product manager of the online *Federal IT Dashboard* performance transparency website. He established a data analytics team that rationalized IT budget & performance data collection and identified savings of more than \$3.6 billion through data-driven reviews with the leaders of government departments and IT leadership.

### Certification, Awards, Training

- 2016 Federal 100 Award (*Link*) winner as the White House OMB leader of the implementation of the Federal IT Acquisition Reform Act (FITARA) across all Federal agencies, including authoring the implementing memorandum.
- White House Office of Management and Budget Outstanding Performance Award, 2016; Cross-Functional Team Award, 2015
- Primary Tools: Salesforce CRM, Tableau Desktop & Server, SQL, Python, R, PHP, drupal

### **Experience**

**Salesforce** - Director, Digital Strategy / Business Transformation Executive

February 2020 - Present

- Authored customer digital transformation vision plans & roadmaps for 30+ Federal Civilian new and renewal accounts for Salesforce "core" products (e.g. CRM, Service, Platform) and Tableau. Built CRM transformation roadmaps and vision plans for USDA, TSA, CBP, HHS, and other civilian agencies. These enterprise-level transformation guides go beyond single use case implementation plans.
- Provided continuous support to Federal Civilian sales account area vice presidents, regional vice presidents, and account executives for honing a relevant message to Federal CIOs and program leaders. Presented directly to executive public sector customers directly in sales and renewal motions to close deals and grow business for key "big bet" individual accounts, in collaboration with sales account executives. This customer-level support directly influenced over \$4m per year in closed deals' additional contract value.
- Led the Salesforce *Executive Center for Government* to convene executive-level public sector customers using Salesforce services to address common technology or business challenges in agencies through day-long intensive sessions with Salesforce executive leadership team (e.g. COO, CFO) in Salesforce Tower. Built and maintained the *Federal Policy Roadmap* and led the roundtable event *Using Policy as a Tailwind for Transformation*. Collaborated with account teams to develop successful agendas for sessions of the Executive Center for Government.
- Presented to customers and industry groups, both as standalone topics (*The Post-FITARA Agency* at Evanta Federal CIO Summit) and panel discussions alongside Federal leaders (on *Customer Experience & Federal Policy* at the ACT-IAC CX Summit).

#### **Institute of Museum and Library Services -** Chief Information Officer

**February 2017 – June 2019** 

- To support a total agency budget managing \$1.15 billion in grants and expenses, managed a total office budget of roughly \$6.6 million per year, split between salaries and contracting/licenses.
- Established agile data development blanket purchase agreement (BPA) modeled on GSA 18F TechFAR examples for higher quality IT services through iterative competition. Used for replacement of legacy grants management system support. Led and authored all procurement steps and documents, including initial notice, solicitation, performance work statement/statement of work, vendor evaluation, government cost estimates.
- Designed and implemented OCIO policy, processes, and portfolio turnaround strategy to address years of staff attrition and technical debt, operating at a 62% budget cut from the prior period. Led overall review of OCIO function to identify current state of IMLS practices, applicable government-wide requirements/practices, and an assessment of all gaps between the two, leading to a multi-year roadmap to address high risks that emerged. Successfully implemented the first five calendar quarters of that roadmap, addressing information security, network configuration, mobile device security, network vulnerability scanning, and multi-factor authentication risks for example. Led information security and FISMA reporting; replaced 3rd party FISMA assessment team with a federal shared

service reducing costs by 65%. Established new Tier I & II help desk team, processes, and training; reduced IT service tickets by 55% over first year; radically re-envisioned what customer support communication, collaboration, and follow-up looks like at the agency; embedded IT customer advocates in each agency program.

### **Incapsulate, LLC** - Senior Consultant

**August 2015 – January 2017** 

- Led research team for U.S. Federal CIO Council's "State of Federal IT" to support training of newly-hired CIOs to U.S. federal government agencies; led interviews with each agency Chief Information Officer at 24 major U.S. federal agencies; analyzed 8 years of performance and oversight data from OMB around 7 major IT policy areas; presented findings to White House OMB federal CIO and full membership of the U.S. Federal CIO Council.
- Provided performance management and IT policy subject matter expertise to the District of Columbia's Office of the Chief Performance
  Officer for government-wide performance metrics and web-based dashboards. Aggregated and coordinated data from the DC Office of
  Unified Communications' CRM system for outreach with each Department. Provided analytical and strategy support for in-person
  workshops between each Deputy Mayor, DC City Administrator, and related executive events.

#### White House Office of Management and Budget - Program Manager / Policy Analyst

May 2012 – August 2015

- Recognized in <u>praise from U.S. Congress</u> and by industry leaders as <u>one of the FCW Federal 100</u> most influential voices in the Federal technology management community for leadership of implementation of FITARA. Served as executive director of the President's Management Council FITARA/FISMA Executive Working Group. Led OMB coordination with Deputy Secretaries, senior executives (CFO, CIO, etc) at all major Federal agencies, and Congress.
- Designed analytical studies of IT management resources, including cost-benefit analyses, quantitative analysis of key performance indicators from diverse sources, and delivered data and analysis products to U.S. Federal Chief Information Officer and Deputy Secretaries of cabinet agencies to direct changes in IT management leading to over \$2 billion of realized cost savings.
- Supported OMB oversight of Federal IT projects; developed testimony to Congress, presentations to Director of OMB; responses to Government Accountability Office (GAO), external remarks and presentations by Federal CIO.
- Served as program manager of the Federal IT Dashboard, COR for development, product enhancements and prioritized backlog items, conducted all budget and invoice reviews and approvals. Migrated to new hosting, saving 73% per year (\$275k per year).

#### **SRA International** - Senior Consultant (at OMB)

February 2009 - May 2012

- Supported design and launch of the Federal IT Dashboard within 60 days, an open government and transparency web application dedicated to strengthening accountability by sharing the government's performance across 800+ major Federal IT projects publicly.
- Used database systems to perform rigorous data standardization, analytics, reporting, and quality assurance on qualitative and quantitative data; built structured query language (SQL) scripts and other tools for data processing.

### Blue State Digital - Strategy Fellow

October 2008 - November 2008

• Strategic political consultant for constituency development and communications using proprietary web tools, social networking, and online community analysis tools to engage target voters.

### **National Security Agency -** *Intelligence Analyst*

**August 2003 – August 2008** 

- Stokes Scholarship Award, providing full undergraduate tuition and stipend.
- Award-winning pioneer and recognized expert in innovative interagency collaboration; integrated blogs, wikis, and social bookmarking platforms into NSA reporting. Authored hundreds of intelligence assessment reports, including some that appeared in the President's Daily Brief (PDB).

### DC Data Community & Data Science DC - Board Member, Co-Organizer

**March 2012 – February 2017** 

• Connects and promotes the work of data professionals in the Washington, DC area. Over 6,000 data scientists, analysts, economists, programmers, researchers, and statisticians, regardless of industry, sector, or technology. (*Link*)

#### **Education**

- University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, 2003 2007 B.A. in Public Policy Analysis, International Security, and Minor in Business Administration
- National Cryptologic School (National Security Agency) Intelligence Analysis Development Program
- Edward Tufte, Analyzing/Presenting Data/Information, in-person course
- Massachusetts Institute of Technology MIT Media Lab Open Leadership Camp (Inaugural cohort participant)

## **Presentations & Publications**

# Talks & Panels

### Customer Experience Summit 2022 (ACT-IAC). Panelist,

Lessons Learned from High Impact Service Providers on their CX Journey (11/15/2022)

### FCW Summit: IT Modernization (Federal Computing Week). Author & Presenter,

*Master Class: The Post-FITARA Agency* (10/5/2022)

### Washington, DC CIO Executive Summit (Evanta a Gartner Company). Panel Moderator,

Starting at Customer Centricity (5/3/2022).

### Salesforce DC World Tour (Salesforce). Panel Moderator,

Digital Transformation in Federal Agencies (4/12/2022).

### IT Modernization Summit 2021 (FedScoop). Author & Presenter,

Using Data Transformation to Guide Federal Innovation (4/28/2021).

FITARA Forum III (MeriTalk). Panelist, Federal Perspective on IT (4/4/2016).

**Jump Start Your Agency IT Transformation (MeriTalk).** Panelist (6/17/2016).

FITARA Breakfast Series (MeriTalk) Author & Presenter, Next Steps in FITARA (6/14/2015).

FITARA Forum (MeriTalk). Author & Presenter, The View from OMB (8/11/2015).

## Other Media

**Podcast: American Council for Technology-Industry Advisory Council (ACT-IAC) (2022).** Author & Presenter, *ICYMI: The CX Journey of High-Impact Service Providers* <a href="https://www.actiac.org/buzz">https://www.actiac.org/buzz</a>

**Video: IT Modernization Summit 2021 (FedScoop).** Author & Presenter, *Using Data Transformation to Guide Federal Innovation* (4/28/2021) https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f EKh30TjRs

Video: Thought Leaders Series (FedScoop). Author & Presenter, Four Lenses of Federal Digital Transformation (2021).

**Podcast:** Carnegie Mellon University (2018). Guest interview, *Interview With IMLS Deputy Director Of Digital And Information Strategy Benjamin Sweezy* <a href="https://amt-lab.org/podcasts-interviews/2018/10/new-podcast-interview-with-">https://amt-lab.org/podcasts-interview-with-</a>

## **Publications**

**Salesforce Blog** (2022) Lead author, *How to Accelerate Digital Transformation with the Technology Modernization Fund* <a href="https://www.salesforce.com/resources/articles/obtaining-technology-modernization-fund/">https://www.salesforce.com/resources/articles/obtaining-technology-modernization-fund/</a>

White House Federal CIO Council (2017) Lead author & researcher, *The State of Federal IT Report (SOFIT)* https://www.cio.gov/resources/sofit/

**White House Office of Management and Budget** (2015) Lead author, *M-15-14 Management and Oversight of Federal Information Technology* 

 $\underline{https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/legacy\_drupal\_files/omb/memoranda/2015/m-15-14.pdf}$ 

**Technology Business Modernization IT-COST Commission** (2017) Commission Participant, *Accelerating the Mission: Recommendations for Optimizing Federal Technology Cost and Value in the Age of FITARA* <a href="https://www.tbmcouncil.org/learn-tbm/the-federal-it-cost-commission/">https://www.tbmcouncil.org/learn-tbm/the-federal-it-cost-commission/</a>